Guide to the Wheeler for Senate Club Records 1940-1946
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula
Wheeler for Senate Club Records
1940-1946
University of Montana, Mansfield Library, Archives and Special Collections The University of Montana--Missoula Missoula, MT 59812 406-243-2053 http://www.lib.umt.edu/asc library.archives@umontana.edu
Mss 109
Wheeler for Senate Club
0.75 linear feet 2 boxes
The Wheeler for Senate Club was formed to re-nominate U.S. Senator Burton K. Wheeler in the 1946 Montana Democratic primary. The collection contains materials produced and collected by the Wheeler for Senate Club.
Historical Note
The Wheeler for Senate Club was formed to re-nominate U.S. Senator Burton K. Wheeler in the 1946 Montana Democratic primary. R. Bailey Stortz, a member of Wheeler's Washington, D.C. staff, became secretary-treasurer for the club, and Sam E. Winn was president. The club was headquartered in Helena, Montana. Wheeler, who had first been elected by Montanans in 1922, and who was one of the most powerful senators in Washington D.C. in the 1930s, was defeated in the 1946 primary by Leif Erickson. Erickson was subsequently defeated in the general election by Republican candidate Zales Ecton.
The collection contains materials produced and collected by the Wheeler for Senate Club. Materials they collected were about and by the Senator and include his voting record, speeches, and newspaper clippings; they used these to establish the case for his re-election. Materials produced by the Club include correspondence, campaign materials, and financial records.
Researchers must use collection in accordance with the policies of Archives and Special Collections, the Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, and The University of Montana-Missoula.
Date and source of acqusition unknown.
Burton K.Wheeler's papers are held by Merrill G. Burlingame Special Collections, Montana State University Libraries.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Wheeler, Burton K. (Burton Kendall), 1882-1975
Stortz, R. Bailey; Wheeler, Burton K. (Burton Kendall),1882-1975; Winn, Sam E.
United States. Congress. Senate--Elections, 1946; Democratic Party (Mont.)
Montana--Politics and government--20th century
Elections--Montana; Political campaigns--Montana
Speeches, addesses, etc., American
Montana
- Correspondence, 1942-1946 (Box-folder 1/1)
- Correspondence, 1946 (Box-folder 1/2)
- Correspondence, undated (Box-folder 1/3)
- Financial records, 1946 (Box-folder 1/4)
- Wheeler's speeches and writings, 1940-1946 (Box-folder 1/5)
- Campaign materials, 1946 (Box-folder 1/6)
- Clippings, 1940-1946 (Box-folder 1/7)
- Clippings, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 1/8)
- Clippings, 1946 (Box-folder 2/1)
- Wheeler's Senate voting record, undated (Box-folder 2/2)
- Erickson and Wheeler, undated (Box-folder 2/3)